Guide to the United Nations Ad Hoc Committee on Slavery records, 1918-1956 and undated, bulk 1949-1951 RL.10028
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
United Nations Ad Hoc Committee on Slavery records
1918-1956 and undated, bulk 1949-1951
bulk
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
United Nations. Ad Hoc Committee on Slavery
RL.10028
5 Linear Feet
In 1949 the United Nations general assembly asked secretary general to create a committee to investigate the status of slavery and the slave trade. The committee, which was active in 1950-1951, was a joint effort of the Economic and Social Council and the International Labour Organization. The collection contains research files, clippings, minutes, notes, and other materials related to the work of the United Nations Ad Hoc Committee on Slavery.
Biographical/Historical note
In 1949 the United Nations general assembly asked secretary general to create a committee to investigate the status of slavery and the slave trade. The committee, which was active in 1950-1951, was a joint effort of the U.N. Economic and Social Council and the International Labour Organization. The committee published their findings in a report in 1951.
Collection Overview
The collection contains research files, clippings, minutes, notes, and other materials related to the work of the United Nations Ad Hoc Committee on Slavery.
Provenance
The United Nations Ad Hoc Committee on Slavery records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer. The records were originally part of the Duke University Library pamphlet collection. The collection may have originated from Bruno Lasker, representative to the Committee, however no definitive evidence of the individual source of the records was found.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Slavery; Southeast Asia; Forced Labor; Slavery Convention (1926); Arabian Penninsula; United Nations. Ad Hoc Committee on Slavery; United Nations. Economic and Social Council; Lasker, Bruno
- Ad Hoc Committee on Slavery records, 1918-1956 and undated, bulk 1949-1951; bulk; 1
  - Abstracts and Notes: Slavery Serfdom Peonage Forced Labor and Other forms of Servitude 19971-1, circa 1950; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Abstracts and Notes: Slavery Serfdom Peonage Forced Labor and Other forms of Servitude, Volume II 19971-2, 1950-1951; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Abstracts and Notes: Slavery Serfdom Peonage Forced Labor and Other forms of Servitude, Volume III 19971-3, 1950-1951; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Abstracts and Notes: Slavery Serfdom Peonage Forced Labor and Other forms of Servitude, Volume IV 19971-4, 1950-1951; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Abstracts, Notes and References, Volume V 19971-5, 1950; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Abstracts, Notes and References, Volume VI 19971-6, undated; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Abstracts, Notes and References, Volume VII 19971-7, undated; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Abstracts, Notes and References, Volume VIII 19971-8, undated; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Freedom of Person, Extracts from (and notes on) sources, I 19971-9, undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Freedom of Person, Extracts from (and notes on) sources, II 19971-10, undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Freedom Person, volume III 19971-11, undated; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Slavery, Library of Congress Draft Bibliography 19971-12, 1950; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Committee Reports 19971-13, 1950-1953; 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Report on Legal and Illegal Forms of Forced Labor in the United States, Prepared by Rowland Watts, National Secretary Workers Defense League 19971-14, 1951; 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Results from a Questionnaire on Slavery and Servitude, circa 1950-1951; 5 folders (Box 4)
  - Report: Slavery, the Slave Trade, and other forms of Servitude 19971-16, 1953; 1 folder (Box 4)
  - Slavery and Other Forms of Servitude, New Materials 19971-17, 1955-1956; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - International Labor Office, draft text, Labour Policy in Netherlands India 19971-18, circa 1944; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Slavery - League of Nations 19971-19, circa 1931-1951; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - United Nations Economic and Social Council Minutes Relating to the Problems of Slavery 19971-20, 1949-1953; 2 folder (Box 5)
  - United Nations Economic and Social Council Minutes Relating to Survey of Forced Labor 19971-21, 1949-1950; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - United Nations General Assembly - Slavery 19971-22, 1949-1953; 1 folders (Box 5)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Slavery Minutes, part I 19971-23, 1950; 1 of 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Slavery Minutes, part I 19971-23, 1950; 2 of 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Slavery Minutes, part II 19971-24, 1950; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Slavery Minutes, part III 19971-25, 1950-1951; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Slavery Minutes, part IV 19971-26, 1951; 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Slavery Minutes, part V 19971-27, 1951; 1 folders (Box 6)
  - Inquiry into Prevailing Conditions Questionnaire, etc., part I 19971-28, 1949-1950; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Inquiry Into Prevailing Conditions, part II 19971-29, 1950-1951; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - E/AC 33L.1, Reports and Definitions by the Committee, 19971-30, 1950-1951; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Draft Report, 19971-31, 1951; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Draft Report, 19971-32, 1951; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Forced Labor, Compulsory Labor, Memoranda, Notes, Clippings, 19971-33, 1929-1949 and undated; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Forced Labor, Compulsory Labor: Memoranda, Notes, Clippings, part II, 19971-34, 1928-1929, 1943-1954; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Memoranda by Individual Members of the Ad Hoc Committee, part I, 19971-35, 1951; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Memoranda by Individual Members of the Ad Hoc Committee, part II, 19971-36, 1951; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Memoranda by Individual Members of the Committee, 19971-37, 1951; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Memoranda by Individual Members of the Committee, 19971-38, 1951; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Samples of Publicity, 19971-39, 1946-1953; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Slavery in Arabia by Silvia Bailes, 19971-40, 1951; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Labor in the Pacific by anita Bradley, 19971-41, 1938-1939, 1944; 1 folders (Box 8)
  - Materials and Notes: Forced Labor and Quasi-Slavery in Portuguese West Africa, 19971-42, 1925-1953; 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Labor Conditions in Southeast Asia, Introduction, 19971-43, undated; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Labor Conditions in Southeast Asia, part I, 19971-43, undated; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Labor Conditions in Southeast Asia, part II: III Employment and Unemployment, undated, 19971-44, 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Labor Conditions in Southeast Asia, part II: IV Compulsory Labor, 19971-44, undated; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Labor Conditions in Southeast Asia, part II: V. Labor remuneration and Forms of Payment, 19971-44, undated; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Labor Conditions in Southeast Asia, part II: VI. Other conditions of Labor, 19971-44, undated; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Labor Conditions in Southeast Asia, part III: VII. Government Regulation, 19971-45, undated; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Labor Conditions in Southeast Asia, part III: VIII. Labor Organization, 19971-45, undated; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Labor Conditions in Southeast Asia, part III: IX. Labor Migration, X. Labor Education, XI. Labor and Social Wealth, 19971-45, undated; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Slavery and Peonage - USA, "Sale For Adoption," Clippings and Memoranda, 19971-46, 1393-1950; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 19971-47, 1933, 1943-circa 1953; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Supplementary Material: Slavery and Other Forms of Servitude, 19971-48, 1926-1950, undated; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Slavery and Servitude: Bibliographies and Assorted Notes on Likely Sources, 19971-49, circa 1940-1950s and undated; 2 of 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Slavery and Servitude: Bibliographies and Assorted Notes on Likely Sources, 19971-49, circa 1940-1950s and undated; 3 of 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Periodical Issues and Reprints, 19971-50, 1918-1953; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Periodical Issues and Reprints, "Negro Episcopalians in Ante-Bellum North Carolina," by John Hope Franklin, 19971-50, undated; 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Periodical Issues and Reprints, 19971-51, 1933-1950; 2 folders (Box 10)